aston.ac.uk 2015-06-08

# Cookies & privacy

The information on this page refers to the main Aston University website (www.aston.ac.uk) and does not cover other websites which may be linked to from the Aston site. 

### What is a cookie?

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site.

Find out more about cookies:

  * [Information Comissioner's Office guidance on cookie regulations](http://www.ico.gov.uk/for_organisations/privacy_and_electronic_communications/the_guide/~/media/documents/library/Privacy_and_electronic/Practical_application/guidance_on_the_new_cookies_regulations.ashx "ICO guidance on cookie regulations") (PDF)

### What cookies does the Aston University website use?

Aston University uses cookies to improve your experience of our website. 

Cookie | Name  | Purpose  | Further information  
---|---|---|---  
Essential site cookie |  ASP.NetSessionId  |  This is a unique id given to every user to help the website maintain session information for the Microsoft .NET framework that runs our website. This cookie is deleted as soon as you leave the Aston website. |  [How and why session IDs are reused in ASP.NET](http://support.microsoft.com/kb/899918 "ASP.NET session IDs")  
Cookies set by intranet sites used by Aston staff and students |   | 

Some parts of our site are password-protected and only used by staff and students. These intranet sites may use cookies, which are essential for their operation. 

As they are only used on intranet sites, these cookies are excluded from the EU Cookie Directive.

|  [Information Comissioner's Offfice guidance on cookie regulations](http://www.ico.gov.uk/for_organisations/privacy_and_electronic_communications/the_guide/~/media/documents/library/Privacy_and_electronic/Practical_application/guidance_on_the_new_cookies_regulations.ashx "ICO guidance") (PDF)  

### Third-party cookies

Cookie | Name  | Purpose  | Further information  
---|---|---|---  
Google  Analytics                 |  _utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmz | 

This website uses Google Analytics, a tool which uses cookies to provide us with information on how people use the Aston site. This information helps us to analyse the performance of the site so we can make improvements. 

These cookies don’t collect information that identifies individual visitors to the website. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and is therefore anonymous.

Yandex   
Metrica | yandexuid   
yabs-sid  
|  This website uses Yandex Metrica, a tool which uses cookies to provide us with information on how people use the Aston site. This information helps us to analyse the performance of the site so we can make improvements.   |  [Yandex's privacy policy](http://legal.yandex.com/privacy/ "Yandex's privacy ")   
   
YouTube cookies        
|                 | We embed videos from our official YouTube channels using YouTube’s privacy-enhanced mode. This mode may set cookies on your computer once you click on the YouTube video player, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode.  |  [YouTube's privacy enhanced mode for embedded videos](http://support.google.com/youtube/bin/answer.py?hl=en-GB&answer=141046? "Privacy enhanced mode")  
Cookies set by Twitter | pid  
guest_id  
k  
js  
| These cookies are created by Twitter. In this case they are present because a Twitter widget or button is being used on the Aston website.  |  [Twitter's privacy policy](http://twitter.com/privacy "Twitter's privacy policy")  
  
How to control or delete these cookies   

Aston University uses cookies to improve your experience of our website. We do not use cookies to collect personally identifiable information about you.

If you wish to restrict or block the cookies which are set by our website, you can do this through your browser settings. The [About Cookies website](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "About Cookies") contains step-by-step guides to controling or deleting cookies on a wide variety of browsers. 

For information on how to control or remove cookies on your mobile phone or other devices, please refer to the device's manual or manufacturer's website.

To opt-out of third-parties collecting any data regarding your interaction on our website, please refer to their websites for further information. 

### Feedback

We welcome your thoughts and comments \- complete a feedback form.  

## Privacy

This privacy policy sets out how Aston University uses and protects any information that you give us when you use our website.

We are committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

Aston University may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. 

### What we collect

Aston University does not capture or store your personal information when you access our website, unless you voluntarily agree to give us your personal details by completing an online form. In this case, the personal data you provide will be used exclusively to provide you with information about the University.

We may collect the following information:

  * name

  * contact information, such as your address, email address or phone number

  * information on your preferences and interests

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service

### Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

### Controlling your personal information

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so.

Under the Data Protection Act 1998, you may request details of personal information which we hold about you. If you would like a copy of this information, please complete a University Data Subject Access Request Form and send it, along with a cheque for £10 (to cover administration costs for collating this information), made payable to "Aston University", to: 

 John Walter  
Data Protection Officer  
University Communications  
Aston University  
Aston Triangle  
Birmingham      
B4 7ET

 If you have any questions about Aston University’s Data Protection Policy please write to our Data Protection Officer at the above address or email [j.g.walter@aston.ac.uk](mailto:j.g.walter@aston.ac.uk "Contact John Walter")

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please contact us as soon as possible. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
